Vishal Priyadarshi

Sr. Web Developer



Email: vishalyzd@gmail.com

Contact: +91 872 615 5333

Portfolio:
https://vishalyzd.github.io/

ABOUT ME

Creating beautifully designed, intuitive and functional websites is my passion. Over the past 6 years, I have worked for some of the best agencies and wonderful clients worldwide to create some award-winning Web Applications and their maintenance.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

Engineering- Christ University, Bengaluru - India 2012 - 2016- CGPA - 3.7/5

Class 12th - The Modern World School, Lucknow - India 2011 - 2012 - 75%

Class 10th - The Modern World School, Lucknow - India 2009 - 2010 - 79%

LANGUAGES / SKILL

Web Development, React, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, AWS SES, Digital Marketing, DNS Server Management, Microsoft Support, AWS, PHP, Laravel, Event Management, Email Marketing, SMTP, HTML Emails, Linux VPS Migration, CRM, Full Stack Development, Software Architecture, PL/SQL, ORACLE LSH.

EXPERIENCE

Sr. Web Developer - Xiphias XPay.Life Pvt Ltd - A Fintech firm, Bengaluru, India- Feb 2022 - Present.

 Designed, developed, and maintained XPay.Life's main website, increasing traffic by 50% through speed optimization and on-page SEO. Utilized React, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and

- Node.js.
- Implemented cost-effective bulk email blast using AWS SES, reducing expenses by 90%.
 Acquired Photoshop skills for design purposes.
- Reduced CPAs across Facebook, Google, Twitter, and Linkedin by leveraging knowledge in digital marketing.
- Acted as a single point of contact for DNS server management and handled server issues in collaboration with Microsoft Support and AWS.
- Created and hosted 10 Indian Rural Bank websites using React.js.

Sr. Web Developer - Sphere Travel media & Exhibitions, Bengaluru - India 2019 - May 2021.

- Designed, developed, and hosted over 20 websites from scratch for Sphere Travel media
 Exhibitions. Proficient in Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel, and React.
- Developed an Event Management system for appointment booking with payment integration, serving 10K exhibitors and 1 lakh visitors daily.
- Implemented cost-effective email marketing using AWS SES and Whatsapp bulk blaster, saving 90% in expenses. Proficient in SMTP and HTML Emails.
- Successfully migrated more than twenty websites between Linux VPS servers, reducing costs significantly.
- Utilized CRM and website data for analytics and client acquisition.

Full Stack Developer - JSS Webs, Chandigarh - India 2018 - 2019

Onboarding clients, building trust by providing software architecture consultation Designing, developing, hosting & maintaining web apps for pharma clients based in the UK.

Founder - Cyberei Technologies - May 2016 - Feb 2018

Generating Leads, Converting them to clients, building trust by providing software architecture consultation, and developing more than 10 web apps including social media, and e-commerce apps for some tech giants around the world.

ORACLE LSH Developer INTERN - Accenture, Bangalore -India 2015-2016

Developed a PL/SQL module to migrate a database of clinical patients (Zika Virus for GSK) which eventually helped in medicine development.